DANIEL KELLEY, PMP, PMI-ACP

www.linkedin.com/in/daniel-kelley1 • https://github.com/DK-2021

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Adaptable, organized and dependable US Army Special Operations veteran. Someone who has planned, coordinated and executed several programs and projects; connecting with both governmental and non-governmental partners. Transitioning into software engineering with a fundamental understanding of full stack software development. Possess and have maintained a Secret Clearance for more than ten years.

RELEVANT CERTIFICATIONS

- Project Management Professional (PMP), 2021
- Project Management Institute Agile Certified Practitioner (PMI-ACP), 2021
- Microsoft Certified Azure Fundamentals (AZ-900), 2021
- Microsoft Technology Associate Software Development Fundamentals (MTA 98-361), 2021
- NC State University Artificial Intelligence Academy Foundations Course, 2021

EXPERIENCE

Microsoft Software and Systems Academy

Cloud Application Development Student

January 2022 - May 2022

- Selected for a highly competitive program that supports transitioning service members as they gain the professional and technical knowledge necessary to enter the technology industry.
- Focused and studied in **Cloud** Application Development, learning to design, write, build, and support applications and programs.
- Gained fundamental skills in C#, SQL, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Git and Object-Oriented Programming.
- Learned conceptual frameworks for Web Application Development, **ASP.NET MVC**, and **Azure Application Development**.
- Built, modified, and ran more than 100 queries against **T-SQL** databases via **SQL Server Management Studio** for data analysis and interpretation.

95th Civil Affairs Brigade (Army Special Operations)

Assistant Operations Supervisor

October 2020 - January 2022

- Assumed the Operational Supervisor position for four months during a company realignment; maintained both
 positions for four months and managed 15 coworkers to meet all organizational directives.
- Managed the company's classified personnel recovery database; increased the company's compliance from 80% to 100% when audited by a third-party.
- Published over 35 organizational bulletins that were distributed to more than 200 coworkers weekly; informed
 coworkers of company-wide events and notified of career enhancing opportunities.

Civil Affairs Specialist

August 2017 – October 2020

- Coordinated four humanitarian assistance programs valued at \$45,000; enabled the U.S. Embassy access to three strategic locations in Trinidad and Tobago.
- Managed the expenses of **\$20,000 USD** worth of organizational funds while working internationally; utilized the funds appropriately enabling the team to **increase** its overall capacity to achieve objectives.
- Conducted over **90** consultations with host nation partners; **fostered** U.S. Embassy relations with host government, local partners and security forces.

Assistant Operations Administrator

October 2017 - August 2018

- Assisted in development and coordination of an organization validation exercise that stretched over three counties
 in VA; the exercise helped certify over 50 service members to deploy by meeting company requirements.
- Delegated and coordinated over 200 tasks to different teams in support of organizational functions; all tasks'
 deadlines were met and adherence to the enterprise's readiness model standard was maintained.

PROJECTS

Random Restaurant Picker – C#, SQL, XML, XAML

A team project that used an API of a given location to help select a type of restaurant to eat at based on certain user preferences. The user preferences were connected to a local database shared between team members via GitHub.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Criminal Justice, University of Massachusetts, MA